{"title": "Britain!", "listOfQuestions": [
{"question" : "What is the capital of England?",
"correctAnswer": "London",
"wrongAnswers": ["Manchester", "Birmingham", "Liverpool"],
"timeout": 8},

{"question" : "Which river runs through the city of York?",
"correctAnswer": "Ouse",
"wrongAnswers": ["Tees", "Tyne", "Mersey"],
"timeout": 12},

{"question": "Which British monarch was executed in 1649?",
"correctAnswer": "Charles I",
"wrongAnswers": ["Henry VIII", "James I", "George I"],
"timeout": 10},

{"question": "What is the largest city in Scotland?",
"correctAnswer": "Glasgow",
"wrongAnswers": ["Edinburgh", "Aberdeen", "Inverness"],
"timeout": 10},

{"question": "Which mountain range runs along the border between England and Scotland?",
"correctAnswer": "Cumbrian Mountains",
"wrongAnswers": ["Pennines", "Lake District", "Cheviot Hills"],
"timeout": 14},

{"question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?",
"correctAnswer": "Walter Raleigh",
"wrongAnswers": ["Robert Walpole", "William Pitt", "David Lloyd George"],
"timeout": 15},

{"question": "What is the famous prehistoric monument located in Wiltshire, England?",
"correctAnswer": "Stonehenge",
"wrongAnswers": ["Salisbury Cathedral", "Avebury Circle", "Carnac Stones"],
"timeout": 12},

{"question": "Which English county is known for its cider production?",
"correctAnswer": "Herefordshire",
"wrongAnswers": ["Somerset", "Gloucestershire", "Devon"],
"timeout": 15},

{"question": "Who was the leader of the Labour Party and became Prime Minister in 1945?",
"correctAnswer": "Clement Attlee",
"wrongAnswers": ["Winston Churchill", "David Lloyd George", "Neville Chamberlain"],
"timeout": 12},

{"question": "What is the name of the famous music festival held on a farm in Somerset?",
"correctAnswer": "Glastonbury Festival",
"wrongAnswers": ["Reading Festival", "Leeds Festival", "Isle of Wight Festival"],
"timeout": 8},

{"question": "Which city is known for its canals and is often referred to as 'Venice of the North'?",
"correctAnswer": "Birmingham",
"wrongAnswers": ["Manchester", "Leeds", "Liverpool"],
"timeout": 15},

{"question": "Who was the famous British author who wrote 'Pride and Prejudice'?",
"correctAnswer": "Jane Austen",
"wrongAnswers": ["Charlotte Bronte", "Emily Bronte", "Mary Shelley"],
"timeout": 12},

{"question": "What are the names of the famous football clubs based in Manchester?",
"correctAnswer": "Manchester United and Manchester City",
"wrongAnswers": ["Manchester FC and Manchester Lions", "Newcastle United and Newcastle City", "Manchester Hotspur and the Manchester Lions"],
"timeout": 10},

{"question": "Which mountain is located in Wales and has a height of over 1,000 meters?",
"correctAnswer": "Snowdon",
"wrongAnswers": ["Ben Nevis", "Scafell Pike", "Scafell"],
"timeout": 10},

{"question": "Which British monarchs ruled for over 60 years?", 
"correctAnswer":"Victoria and Elizabeth II",
"wrongAnswers":["George III and Charles I","Henry VIII and Richard III","Elizabeth I"],
"timeout":15},

{"question": "What is the name of the famous university located in Oxford?", 
"correctAnswer":"University of Oxford",
"wrongAnswers":["University of Cambridge","Imperial College London","University College London"],
"timeout":10},

{"question": "Which city is known for its industrial heritage and is often referred to as 'Steel City'?", 
"correctAnswer":"Sheffield",
"wrongAnswers":["Leeds","Bradford","Hull"],
"timeout":15},

{"question": "Who was the famous British scientist who developed the theory of evolution through natural selection?", 
"correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin",
"wrongAnswers":["Isaac Newton","Galileo Galilei","Albert Einstein"],
"timeout":10},

{"question": "What is the name of the famous British rock band that formed in Liverpool in 1960?", 
"correctAnswer":"The Beatles",
"wrongAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","The Who","Queen"],
"timeout":10},

{"question": "Which British monarch was known as the 'Merry Monarch'?", 
"correctAnswer":"Charles II",
"wrongAnswers":["James I","Charles I","Henry VIII"],
"timeout":10},

{"question": "What is the name of the famous British novelist who wrote '1984' and 'Animal Farm'?", 
"correctAnswer":"George Orwell",
"wrongAnswers":["J.R.R. Tolkien","A.A. Milne","H.G. Wells"],
"timeout":10}

]}
